last year on Facebook connect 2021
Facebook changed its name to meta and
Mark Zuckerberg showed us his vision for
the metaverse we saw very promising
Concepts and cool looking demos of how
the metaverse would look like and I for
one was very excited one year later and
after spending more than 10 billion
dollars on this year's meta connect we
got to see how much progress meta has
made on building the vision of the
metaverse that was announced a year ago
and although there are two announcements
that I'm very excited about I did expect
something a little bit better after 10
billion dollars spent and 10 000
employees working on it the biggest
thing that was announced was the quest
Pro a new high-end VR headset with a
price tag of 1 500 this headset is more
aimed as a productivity device rather
than some something to only play video
games with the coolest feature about the
quest Pro is the color pass through
passthrough is the ability to see the
space outside of the headset when the
user is wearing the device this allows
for more mixed reality experiences that
I personally like more than VR VR is
cool and all but it makes you completely
disconnect from the outside world with
full color pass through you can still
see the outside world and add a ledger
of digital content to it which is where
I think there are a lot of possibilities
this unlocks experiences like the ones
you can see on this video where instead
of having real monitors you can just
wear the headset and have as many
screens as you like artists could also
take advantage of that as well as people
in all different sorts of jobs on this
year's metaconnect you can really see
Meta trying to position VR as not just a
toy but as something we will use for
work Mira partnered with Microsoft to
bring Microsoft teams word excel
PowerPoint and Outlook as well as
Microsoft Windows 365 to the quest they
also announced Xbox cloud gaming and the
Xbox game pass coming to the quest and
they also said that Gamers will be able
to connect and play with their XBox
controller basically using the quest as
a giant private screen that they can
play on at any time avatars are also
getting better they are becoming more
expressive thanks to the face tracking
of the quest Pro you can see here how
they can tell when someone is talking
moving their arm or even eating they
also now have legs last year avatars
were just floating legless torsos which
makes them look a little bit creepy but
they will now have legs which according
to Mark is a surprisingly hard thing to
do another cool thing that they showed
us was that it's not ready yet are super
realistic avatars they're called full
body codec avatars and even though they
are not ready yet they look really
really cool they are also much more
expressive than the current ones and
they can capture things like frowning
your eyes moving eyebrows and more they
also support different lighting which
makes them way more realistic personally
I don't see myself using VR to attend
work meetings if it's not using avatars
like this because generating these kinds
of avatars takes a long time they are
not ready to be used yet but there is
something called instant avatars which
are a little bit lower resolution
compared to the others but if you have a
phone you can scan your face and wait
for a couple of hours and you will be
able to get the instant Avatar ready to
use on your phone or VR now even though
the announcements so far haven't been
mind-blowing there is a prototype of a
project that I think it's super cool and
I hope it succeeds there is a headset
different from the quest that is secret
because they didn't show it to us that
has a motor neural control as you can
see on this video just by move in your
thumb you can check your messages and by
turning your hand putting your fingers
together or letting them go you can even
take a photo here here you can see how
this motor neural control is being used
to play and move a character in a game
it can be trained to learn and detect
the tiniest movements a hand can make to
get something like what you see here
where the person is controlling the
character on the game with almost no
hand movement at all this I think is
incredibly cool and it is the thing that
I am excited about the most now I want
to know what you think what do you think
of the meters and what do you think of
what Mera is doing I have seen many
people online mocking Mark and being
very cynical of what he's trying to make
but I personally remain optimistic that
one way or another The Innovation and
the r d that is being put on this space
is eventually going to trickle down and
benefit all of us oh and one thing I
almost forgot is that unlike last year
this year nfts were not mentioned at all
which is interesting so that's it for
this video let me know in the comments
the answer to those questions what do
you think of the metaverse do you think
is BS and what do you think of what meta
is doing do you think they're crazy do
you think they're going to succeed I'm
very curious to know what you have to
say please leave the comments below and
I will see you there and don't forget as
always if you want to learn to code and
you want to do it for free with me click
the link below and I will see you there
with many many free courses that you can
take right now for free see you in the
next one stay free come zamina bye